# **Chris Johnson**

1486 W. 3300 S., WVC, Utah 843119 | 7cdjohnson7@gmail.com | (801) 898-0236 | rehpotsirhc.github.io

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I want to be challenged. Programming is fun when it's challenging and involves deep thought. I'm looking for a role where my time is spent analyzing a difficult problem to understand it, decomposing it into a coherent logical structure, and writing algorithms to optimally solve it. Some of my career has had me do this and some of it has been too shallow to keep me interested. I do not want an easy role where the primary job is basic data pushing, i.e., accepting input, applying simple business logic, and database storage. My ideal career path has me writing more machine learning algorithms and working closely with super smart machine learning, artificial intelligence, and data scientist experts. Take a look at rehpotsirhc.github.io.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

**Dealertrack (Cox Automotive)** Sandy, Utah August 2016 - Present

Software Engineer

- Integral team member of a large, multi-team initiative to modernize a large SaaS application from RPG/DB2 to microservices written in C#/.Net Core and hosted in AWS
- → Stepped-up as team-lead part way through project after company reorganization
- → Practiced Scaled Agile Methodology and used automated build/deployments to facilitate continuous delivery

**Utah State University** Logan , Utah January 2015 - August 2016

Machine Learning and Computational Biology Researcher and Lab Manager

- → Built **optimization software** and successfully applied it to fitting two biological models.
- → Collaborated closely with the Institute of Systems Biology on modelling research.
- → Increased speed of biological simulation software (Java) over 10 fold.

Orchid Event Solutions (Visit Salt Lake) Salt Lake City , Utah December 2013 - August 2014

Software Engineer

- Reduced website creation time over 25% by automating development, build and deployment processes.
- → Led a successful devops migration to newer technologies including TFS and Release Management.
- → Practiced Agile Methodology on a small, cross-functional team

Carnections, Inc. Salt Lake City , Utah June 2009 - December 2013

Co-Owner, Founder and Webmaster

- → Designed, programmed, and maintained its website, carnections.com
- → Significantly expanded online presence using search engine optimization (SEO)

## **SKILLS and TECHNOLOGIES**

- → Full stack, APIs, microservices, UI, speech and language processing, data vis., machine learning
- → C#, .NET Framework and Core, Angular, Java, MSSQL, MySQL, Python, Javascript, Matlab, Docker, Git, TFS, AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, Lambda, Aurora, S3, Dynamo)

# **EDUCATION**

**Utah State University** Logan, Utah July 2016

Computer Science, M.S., GPA 3.89

- → Emphasis in machine learning, optimization, and computational biology
- Thesis: Fitting a Multiscale Biofilm Model using a Parallelized Multi-objective Genetic Algorithm

University of Utah Salt Lake City, Utah May 2012

Psychology, B.S., GPA 3.75

University of Utah Salt Lake City, Utah May 2012

Philosophy, B.S., GPA 3.75

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- → Third author on Bridging the multiscale gap: Identifying cellular parameters from multicellular data
  - Primary contribution was developing parameter searching software to fit model
- → Third author on Cell Death as a Trigger for Morphogenesis
  - Primary contribution was developing and programming software model of biofilm cell death

### **SUMMARY**

Back-end web, application, and restful API developer with 8 years of experience across the full stack, primarily using **C#**, **.NET**, **MSSQL**, and **Javascript**. More recent experience includes **Angular**, **AWS**, **MySql**, **.Net Core**, **and microservice**-oriented architecture.

Optimization and computational biology researcher with 2 years experience **model fitting** using **machine learning** techniques, including search algorithms, neural networks, regression, clustering and feature extraction programmed in **Matlab, Python** and **Java**. Creative, analytical thinker with excellent logical reasoning ability and superb written communication skills. I am a curious, life-long learner committed to excelling at everything I do.